Guide to the Henry Noble MacCracken Papers, 1907 - circa 1968
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Henry Noble MacCracken Papers
1907 - circa 1968
MacCracken, H. N. (Henry Noble), 1880-1970
167 cubic feet (169 boxes, 1 OV folder)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, contracts, publications, and other materials pertaining to Henry Noble MacCracken's tenure as president of Vassar College.
Biographical Note
Dr. Henry Noble MacCracken (1880-1970), was born in Toledo, Ohio, in 1880. He graduated from New York University in 1900 with a degree in English literature, and returned to earn a master's degree in English in 1904. He went on to Harvard University for a second Master's and received his Ph.D. in 1907. He taught at Harvard University, Yale University, and Smith College before coming to Vassar in 1915.
MacCracken was Vassar's fifth president and his tenure was the longest in the college's history. He sparked controversy because of his advocacy for women's suffrage and his liberal views toward education and politics. He was fired in 1918 because of these views but returned to office after student-faculty protests and the resignation of three trustees. MacCracken contributed many important things to Vassar including service as an English professor and the endowment of a chair in the English department. He also worked to bring more foreign students to Vassar, increased student involvement in college policy making, established the Euthenics Department (1923), and supported Hallie Flanagan Davis in her work on the Experimental Theatre. MacCracken worked tirelessly through both world wars, spearheading Vassar's many contributions to the war effort. He also worked with the Red Cross and served as director of educational work on the New York Council of Home Defense.
MacCracken was also involved in many local and national organizations, both during and subsequent to his time at Vassar. He was a member of the National Committee of the League to Enforce Peace, an organizer for the Dutchess County Health Association, (the first county public health organization in the United States), and one of the creators of the Kosciuszko Foundation to promote relations between the United States and Poland. He was a key figure in the foundation of Sarah Lawrence College in 1926, a member of the National Conference of Christians and Jews, and chairman of the conference's international meeting in London.
MacCracken also spent a significant amount of his time lecturing, at Vassar as well as at other institutions across the country. Topics included his religious views, the United Nations, civil liberties and English literature, among others. He also had an interest in local history and wrote several books on the Poughkeepsie area and Vassar. Titles included The Family on Gramercy Park, The Hickory Limb, Old Dutchess Forever! The Story of an American County, and Blithe Dutchess: The Flowering of an American County from 1812.
MacCracken died May 7, 1970 in Poughkeepsie at the age of 89.
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, contracts, publications, and other materials pertaining to Vassar College Trustees and administration, Buildings and Grounds, faculty, students, alumnae, programs, and activities, 1914-1950; to the World Youth Congress of 1938; to his own teaching activities; to Sarah Lawrence College, 1926-1937; to World War I, 1915-1920; to the Dutchess County Health Association, 1919-1945; and to the Kosciuszko Foundation (New York City), 1923-1962. Correspondence files from his personal involvement in such organizations as the American Civil Liberties Union, the Congregational Church, American Red Cross, International Migration Service, National Student Federation, the Southern Women's Educational Alliance, and the National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1915-1946. Personal and business correspondence with Felix Frankfurter, F.J. Furnivall, Herbert Hoover, Charles Evans Hughes, G.L. Kittredge, Herbert Lehman, John M. Manley, Henry Morgenthau, Michael Idvorsky Pupin, Eleanor Roosevelt, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Constance Rourke, Alfred E. Smith, William Howard Taft, M. Carey Thomas, Mary E. Woolley, and others, 1915-1946. His speeches, manuscripts, typescripts, publications, and related correspondence, some of which concern Dutchess County history. Scrapbook of letters and clippings concerning his radio talk on religious liberty in the United States, 1928. Letters and a notebook of miscellaneous records from the U.S. Committee for the Care of European Children, 1940-1942. Photographs and biographical information.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965; Furnivall, Frederick James, 1825-1910; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948; Kittredge, George Lyman, 1860-1941; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963; Manley, John M.; Morgenthau, Henry, 1891-1967; Pupin, Michael Idvorsky, 1858-1935; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Rourke, Constance, 1885-1941; Smith, Alfred Emanuel, 1873-1944; Taft, William Howard, 1857-1930; Thomas, M. Carey (Martha Carey), 1857-1935; Woolley, Mary Emma, 1863-1947
Organizations:
Vassar College. Board of Trustees; Vassar College--Buildings; Vassar College--Presidents; Vassar College--Administration; Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Faculty; Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae; World Youth Congress (1938); Sarah Lawrence College; Dutchess County Health Association; Kosciuszko Foundation; American Civil Liberties Union; American Red Cross; International Migration Service; National Student Federation; Southern Women's Educational Alliance; National Conference of Christians and Jews; United States Committee for the Care of European Children
Subjects:
Congregational churches--United States; Charities; International relief; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1939-1945--Europe--Civilian relief; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women--Education; Radio programs; Polish Americans; Children--Europe; Social work with children--Europe; College presidents; College teachers
Places:
United States--Emigration and immigration; United States--Religious life and customs; United States--Social conditions
Document Types:
Correspondence; Financial records; Photographs; Reports; Scrapbooks
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Presidents
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, February 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, October 2023.
Acquisition Information
Transfer from the Office of the President as well as gifts from the MacCracken family.
Series List
- Series I. Trustees and Administration, 1915-1946; (Boxes 1-16)
  Trustees and Administration, 1915-1920
  Trustees and Administration, 1920-1923
  Trustees and Administration, 1923-1925
  Trustees and Administration, 1925-1927
  Trustees, 1927-1929
  Administration, 1927-1929
  Administration and Endowment, 1928-1932
  Trustees, 1929-1932
  Trustees and Administration, 1932-1934
  Trustees and Administration, 1934-1938
  Trustee Committees, etc., 1934-1938
  Trustees and Administration, 1938-1941
  Trustees and Administration, 1941-1946
  V.C. 50th Anniversary
  College Endowment, 1915-1917
  College Reconstruction Fund, 1918-1919
- Series II. Buildings and Grounds, 1915-1949; (Boxes 16-19)
- Series III. Faculty, 1914-1945; (Boxes 19-50)
  Faculty, 1914-1916
  Faculty, 1916-1918
  Faculty, 1918-1920
  Faculty, 1920-1926
  Faculty, 1920-1922
  Faculty, 1922-1924
  Faculty, 1924-1926
  Faculty, 1926-1928
  Faculty, 1928-1930
  Faculty, 1930-1932
  Faculty, 1932-1934
  Faculty, 1934-1935
  Faculty, 1935-1936
  Faculty, 1936-1939
  Faculty, 1939-1940
  Faculty, Aug 1940 - July 1941
  Faculty, 1941-1943
  Faculty, 1943-1945
  Former Faculty
- Series IV. Students, 1915-1950; (Boxes 51-57)
  Students, 1915 - Aug 1920
  Students, Aug 1920 - Aug 1924
  Students' Records, 1920-1924
  Students, 1924-1934
  Students, 1934-1938
  Students, 1938-1950
- Series V. Alumnae, 1915-1945; (Boxes 57-63)
  General
  Alumnae, 1915-1920
  Alumnae, 1920-1924
  Alumnae, 1924-1927
  Alumnae, 1927-1930
  Alumnae, 1930-1934
  Alumnae, 1934-1938
  Alumnae, 1938-1945
- Series VI. Academic Lectures, 1931-1939; (Boxes 63-64)
  Invitations, Aug 1931-1936
  Lectures, 1932-1935
  Preachers, 1933-1935
  Lectures, 1936/1937 - 1937/1938
  Preachers, 1935/1936 - 1938/1939
- Series VII. Miscellaneous within Vassar College, 1914-1943; (Boxes 65-76)
  Miscellaneous within Vassar College, 1914-1920
  Miscellaneous within Vassar College, Aug 1919 - June 1925
  Miscellaneous within Vassar College, July 1, 1925 - Aug. 1, 1929
  Institute for a Christian Basis of World Relations, 14-20 June 1924
  Miscellaneous within Vassar College, 1929-1935
  Miscellaneous within Vassar College, Aug 1935 - Aug 1937
  Miscellaneous within Vassar College, 1938-1943
  World Youth Congress, 1938
  Radicalism - Protests
- Series VIII. H.N. MacCracken's Teaching at Vassar, 1919-1946; (Boxes 76-78)
  Dr. MacCracken's Courses, 1929-1946
  Dr. MacCracken's Class in Drama, 1919/1920
- Series IX. Associations, 1915-1962; (Boxes 78-89)
  Associations, Aug 1919 - Aug 1923
  V.C. Publicity and Publications, Aug 1919 - Aug 1923
  Associations, Aug 1922 - Aug 1926
  Schools, Aug 1922 - Aug 1926
  V.C. Publications, Aug 1922 - Aug 1926
  Other Colleges, Aug 1918- Aug 1923
  Other Colleges, Aug 1922- Aug 1926
  Associations, July 1923 - Aug 1932
  Colleges, July 1923 - Aug 1932
  Seven Colleges, 1928-1936
  Five College Conference, 1926-1935
  Sarah Lawrence College
  War Correspondence, 1915-1920
  Dutchess County Health Association, 1915-1945
  Kosciuszko Foundation, 1923-1934
  Kosciuszko Foundation, 1934-1962
- Series X. Personal Organizations, 1915-1946; (Boxes 89-96)
  Personal Organizations, 1915-1924
  Personal Organizations, Aug 1921 - Aug 1926
  Personal Organizations, 1927-1929
  Personal Organizations, Aug 1929-1936
  Personal Organizations, Aug 1936 - July 1940
  Personal Organizations, 1941-1946
  National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1939-1946
- Series XI. Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence and Business, 1915-1946; (Boxes 96-110)
  Personal, 1915-1921
  Personal, Aug 1921 - July 1924
  Personal, 1923-1926
  Personal, 1927-1940
  Personal Correspondence, Aug 1926 - Aug 1931
  Miscellaneous Correspondence, Aug 1926-1928
  Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1928-1933
  Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence, July 1931 - July 1936
  Miscellaneous Correspondence, Aug 1935 - Aug 1938
  Personal Correspondence, 1936-1940
  Personal Correspondence, 1940-1943
  Personal Correspondence, August 1943-1946
- Series XII. Biographical Information and Personal Publications, 1907-1946; (Boxes 111-117)
  Bibliographical
  Recognition
  MacCracken Family
  Publications, Speeches and Misc Professional Activities, 1907-1946
  Speeches, 1923-1935
- Series XIII. Unprocessed Personal Material, circa 1920 - circa 1968; (Boxes 118-167)
Container List
- SERIES I. TRUSTEES AND ADMINISTRATION, 1915-1946
  - Trustees and Administration, 1915-1920
    - Superintendent, March 1915-Feb 1918 (Folder 1.1)
    - Superintendent, Feb 1918-June 1920 (Folder 1.2)
    - Director of Halls, 1916-1919 (Folder 1.3)
    - A: Trustees: Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 1.4)
    - Trustees Committee on Art and Art Collections (Folder 1.5)
    - Committee on Administrating Policy (Folder 1.6)
    - Alumnae Trustees (Folder 1.7)
    - Auditor's report, years ending June 30: 1918, 1919 (Folder 1.8)
    - B: Trustees: Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 1.9)
    - Budget system (Folder 1.10)
    - Budget, 1915-1916 (Folder 1.11)
    - Budget figures of treasurer, 1916-1917 (Folder 1.12)
    - Budget, 1917-1918 (Folder 1.13)
    - Budget, 1920-1921 (Folder 1.14)
    - C: Trustees: Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 1.15)
    - Building Committee (Folder 1.16)
    - College accounting (Folder 1.17)
    - Trustee Committee, 1917-1918 (Folder 1.18)
    - Conferences: Treasurer (Folder 1.19)
    - Conferences: Trustees (Folder 1.20)
    - D: Trustees: Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 1.21)
    - Dimock, George E., trustee (Folder 1.22)
    - E: Trustees: Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 1.23)
    - Executive Committee: General correspondence (Folder 1.24)
    - Trustees Executive Committee: Investment Committee (Folder 1.25)
    - Trustees Executive Committee: Minutes, 10 March 1915 (Folder 1.26)
    - Executive Committee: Minutes and dockets (Folder 1.27)
    - Executive Committee Ruling (Folder 1.28)
    - Faculty and Studies Committee meeting (Folder 1.29)
    - Faculty and Studies Committee: General Correspondence (Folder 1.30)
    - Fiftieth Anniversary (Folder 1.31)
    - General correspondence, Trustees (Folder 1.32)
    - Gowns: Trustees (Folder 1.33)
    - Committee on Grounds: Report, 1914/1915 (etc.) (Folder 1.34)
    - H: Trustees: Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 1.35)
    - Hearer charges (Folder 1.36)
    - Mr. Houck, trustee (Folder 1.37)
    - Income statement (Folder 1.38)
    - L: Trustees: Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 1.39)
    - League of Red Cross Societies (Folder 1.40)
    - M: trustees: Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 1.41)
    - Local Committee Reports (Folder 1.42)
    - Memorial Tablet Committee (Folder 1.43)
    - Minutes of the Board of Trustees (Folder 1.44)
    - Committee on Nominations (Folder 1.45)
    - P: Trustees: Miscellaneous correspondence (Folder 1.46)
    - Library Committee (Folder 1.47)
    - Pratt, C. M., trustee: Correspondence (Folder 1.48)
    - Pratt, C. M., trustee: Correspondence, 1918-June 1920 (Folder 1.49)
    - President's Fund (Folder 1.50)
    - President's leave-of-absence for war work (Folder 1.51)
    - President's Office Expense (Folder 1.52)
    - President's report, 1915/1916 (Folder 1.53)
    - President's report, 1916/1917 (Folder 1.54)
    - President's report, 1917/1918 (Folder 1.55)
    - President's report, 1918/1919 (Folder 1.56)
    - Trustees: Miscellaneous (Folder 1.57)
    - Trustees (Folder 1.58)
    - R: Trustees (Folder 1.59)
    - S: Trustees: Miscellaneous (Folder 1.60)
    - Reports (Folder 1.61)
    - Superintendent of buildings, Mr. Sagar (Folder 1.62)
    - Secretary of the Board of Trustees (Folder 1.63)
    - Treasurer's Advisory Committee (Folder 1.64)
    - Treasurer: Miscellaneous, 1915-1917 (Folder 1.65)
    - Treasurer: Miscellaneous, 1917-1920 (Folder 1.66)
    - Treasurer's reports, 1914-1918 (Folder 1.67)
    - Treasurer's reports, 1918-1920 (Folder 1.68)
    - Treasurer re: salaries, March 1915 - March 1920 (Folder 1.69)
    - Trustees' meeting (Folder 1.70)
    - Trustee, suggestion for (Folder 1.71)
    - Ways and Means Committee (Folder 1.72)
  - Trustees and Administration, 1920-1923
    - Trustees: minutes (Folder 2.1)
    - Director of Halls (Folder 2.2)
    - General Manager, Mr. Gillespie (Folder 2.3)
    - Messenger Room (Folder 2.4)
    - Superintendent of Buildings, Mr. Sagar (Folder 2.5)
    - Superintendent of Grounds, Mr. Downer (Folder 2.6)
    - Applications and Recommendations, Apr-May 1922 (Folder 2.7)
    - Applications and Recommendations, May-Aug 1922 (Folder 2.8)
    - Trustees: agenda (Folder 2.9)
    - Trustees: by-laws (Folder 2.10)
    - Statute of Instructions (Folder 2.11)
    - Secretary of the Board of Trustees (Folder 2.12)
    - Treasurer, Mr. Lesher (Folder 2.13)
    - Auditor's report, 1920, 1922, 1923 (Folder 2.14)
    - Banker's Trust Company (Folder 2.15)
    - Salaries (Folder 2.16)
    - Salary endowment fund (Folder 2.17)
    - Treasurer's report (Folder 2.18)
    - Committees: Trustees (Folder 2.19)
    - Art Committee (Folder 2.20)
    - Building Committee (Folder 2.21)
    - Endowment Committee (Folder 2.22)
    - Executive Committee meetings, Sep 1920-March 1922 (Folder 2.23)
    - Executive Committee meetings, May 1922-June 1923 (Folder 2.24)
    - Executive Committee: Correspondence (Folder 2.25)
    - Faculty and Studies Committee meetings (Folder 2.26)
    - Faculty and Studies Committees: Correspondence (Folder 2.27)
    - Finance Committee (Folder 2.28)
    - Grounds Committee (Folder 2.29)
    - Household Management Committee (Folder 2.30)
    - Library Committee (Folder 2.31)
    - Local Committee (Folder 2.32)
    - Committee on Nominations (Folder 2.33)
    - Committee on Spiritual Life (Folder 2.34)
    - Trustees general correspondence (Folder 2.35)
    - Budget, 1923 for 1923/1924 (Folder 2.36)
    - Treasurer: Miscellaneous, Sep 1920-Feb 1922 (Folder 2.37)
    - Treasurer: Miscellaneous, March 1922-June 1925 (Folder 2.38)
    - President's report, June 1921 (Folder 2.39)
    - President's report, June 1922-June 1923 (Folder 2.40)
    - President's fund (Folder 2.41)
    - A: Trustees (Folder 2.42)
    - B: Trustees (Folder 2.43)
    - C: Trustees (Folder 2.44)
    - D: Trustees (Folder 2.45)
    - E: Trustees (Folder 2.46)
    - H: Trustees (Folder 2.47)
    - L: Trustees (Folder 2.48)
    - M: Trustees (Folder 2.49)
    - N: Trustees (Folder 2.50)
    - P: Trustees (Folder 2.51)
    - R: Trustees (Folder 2.52)
    - S: Trustees (Folder 2.53)
    - T: Trustees (Folder 2.54)
    - W: Trustees (Folder 2.55)
  - Trustees and Administration, 1923-1925
    - A: Trustees (Folder 3.1)
    - Art Committee (Folder 3.2)
    - B: Trustees (Folder 3.3)
    - Arthur, George (Folder 3.4)
    - Auditor's report, 1923/1924 (Folder 3.5)
    - Banker's Trust Company (Folder 3.6)
    - Budget Committee (Folder 3.7)
    - 1924/1925 Budget (Folder 3.8)
    - 1924/1925 Budget (Folder 3.9)
    - Buildings Committee (Folder 3.10)
    - C: Trustees (Folder 3.11)
    - Comptroller's Office (Folder 3.12)
    - Comptroller's Office, Nov 1921-June 30, 1921 (Folder 3.13)
    - D: Trustees (Folder 3.14)
    - Comptroller's report, 1923-1925 (Folder 3.15)
    - Current Business Committee (Folder 3.16)
    - Director of Halls (Folder 3.17)
    - Mr. Downer, superintendent of grounds (Folder 3.18)
    - E: Trustees (Folder 3.19)
    - Euthenics Committee (Folder 3.20)
    - Euthenics Committee (Folder 3.21)
    - Endowment Committee (Folder 3.22)
    - Executive Committee, Sep 1923-June 1924 (Folder 3.23)
    - Executive Committee, June 1924-June 1925 (Folder 3.24)
    - Committee on Expenditures, Dec 1924-Jan 1925 (Folder 3.25)
    - Committee on Expenditures, Feb-June 1925 (Folder 3.26)
    - Committee on Expenditures, May-Aug 1924 (Folder 3.27)
    - Committee on Expenditures, Aug-Dec 1924 (Folder 3.28)
    - Committee on Expenditures, Jan-March 1924 (Folder 3.29)
    - Committee on Expenditures, March-May 1924 (Folder 3.30)
    - Finance Committee (Folder 3.31)
    - G: Trustees (Folder 3.32)
    - General correspondence (Folder 3.33)
    - General Faculty and Studies Committee (Folder 3.34)
    - General Manager, Mr. Gillespie, Aug 1923-Sept 1924 (Folder 3.35)
    - General Manager, Mr. Gillespie, Oct 1924-June 1925 (Folder 3.36)
    - Grounds Committee (Folder 3.37)
    - H: Trustees (Folder 4.1)
    - Committee on Household Management (Folder 4.2)
    - J: Trustees (Folder 4.3)
    - K: Trustees (Folder 4.4)
    - L: Trustees (Folder 4.5)
    - Library Committee (Folder 4.6)
    - M: Trustees (Folder 4.7)
    - R: Trustees (Folder 4.8)
    - Memorial Tablet Committee (Folder 4.9)
    - Committee on Museum and Laboratories (Folder 4.10)
    - Music Committee and Trustees (Folder 4.11)
    - N: Trustees (Folder 4.12)
    - Nominating Committee (Folder 4.13)
    - P: Trustees (Folder 4.14)
    - Henry Noble MacCracken Fund for Medieval Literature, 1925 Feb (Folder 4.15)
    - President's report (Folder 4.16)
    - Committee on Religious Life (Folder 4.17)
    - Registrations (Presidents) (Folder 4.18)
    - Mr. Richards, general manager (Folder 4.19)
    - Mr. Sagar, superintendent of buildings (Folder 4.20)
    - Salaries (Folder 4.21)
    - Salary Endowment Fund (Folder 4.22)
    - Secretary of Trustees (Folder 4.23)
    - Committee on Summer Use of Campus (Folder 4.24)
    - T: Trustees (Folder 4.25)
    - W: Trustees (Folder 4.26)
  - Trustees and Administration, 1925-1927
    - A: Trustees (Folder 4.27)
    - Art Committee (Folder 4.28)
    - Automobile owners (Folder 4.29)
    - B: Trustees (Folder 4.30)
    - Committee on the budget (Folder 4.31)
    - Budget controller (Folder 4.32)
    - Committee on Buildings (Folder 4.33)
    - C: Trustees (Folder 4.34)
    - Comptroller, Mr. Cassat (Folder 4.35)
    - Comptroller's reports, June 1924-1926 (Folder 4.36)
    - Comptroller's reports, June 1924-1926 (Folder 4.37)
    - Chapel exemptions (Folder 4.38)
    - Chapel programs (Folder 4.39)
    - Chapel service (Folder 4.40)
    - Consultant in psychiatry (Folder 4.41)
    - D: Trustees (Folder 4.42)
    - Director of Halls (Folder 4.43)
    - Mr. D. Owen (Folder 4.44)
    - Endowment Committee (Folder 4.45)
    - Euthenics Committee (Folder 4.46)
    - Executive Committee (Folder 4.47)
    - Committee on Expenditures (Folder 4.48)
    - F: Trustees (Folder 4.49)
    - Committee on Faculty and Studies (Folder 4.50)
    - Faculty: private data (Folder 4.51)
    - Faculty: residence on campus (Folder 4.52)
    - Finance and Investment Committee (Folder 4.53)
    - G: Trustees (Folder 4.54)
    - Grounds Committee (Folder 4.55)
    - H: Trustees (Folder 5.1)
    - Household Management Committee (Folder 5.2)
    - Trustees' Committee on Insurance (Folder 5.3)
    - Insurance: Faculty (Folder 5.4)
    - Insurance: Faculty (Folder 5.5)
    - J: Trustees (Folder 5.6)
    - K: Trustees (Folder 5.7)
    - L: Trustees (Folder 5.8)
    - Committee on Sarah Lawrence College (Folder 5.9)
    - Legal opinions (Folder 5.10)
    - Trustees: Library Committee (Folder 5.11)
    - M: Trustees (Folder 5.12)
    - Trustees' minutes (Folder 5.13)
    - Trustees' minutes (Folder 5.14)
    - Trustees' Museum Committee (Folder 5.15)
    - Music Committee (Folder 5.16)
    - Committee on Memorial Tablets (Folder 5.17)
    - N: Trustees (Folder 5.18)
    - Nominating Committee (Folder 5.19)
    - P: Trustees (Folder 5.20)
    - Trustees' Committee on Physical Education (Folder 5.21)
    - President's reports (Folder 5.22)
    - Register of funds in trust (Folder 5.23)
    - Responsive readings (Folder 5.24)
    - Mr. Richards, general manager (Folder 5.25)
    - Mr. Richards, general manager (Folder 5.26)
    - Mr. Richards, general manager (Folder 5.27)
    - Mr. Richards, general manager (Folder 5.28)
    - Mr. Richards, general manager (Folder 5.29)
    - S: Trustees (Folder 5.30)
    - Salaries: Comptroller (Folder 5.31)
    - Secretary of Trustees (Folder 5.32)
    - T: Trustees (Folder 5.33)
    - Treasurer (Folder 5.34)
    - Treasurer (Folder 5.35)
    - Trustees' Committee (Folder 5.36)
    - Trustees' Minutes (Folder 5.37)
    - W: Trustees (Folder 5.38)
    - Trustees' Minutes (Folder 5.39)
    - President's reports (Folder 5.40)
    - President's report (Folder 5.41)
    - Secretary of the Board (Folder 5.42)
    - Trustees: Suggestions (Folder 5.43)
  - Trustees 1927-1929
    - A: Trustees (Folder 5.44)
    - B: Trustees (Folder 5.45)
    - C: Trustees (Folder 5.46)
    - D: Trustees (Folder 5.47)
    - E: Trustees (Folder 5.48)
    - F: Trustees (Folder 5.49)
    - H: Trustees (Folder 5.50)
    - J: Trustees (Folder 5.51)
    - L: Trustees (Folder 5.52)
    - L: Trustees (Folder 5.53)
    - M: Trustees (Folder 5.54)
    - N: Trustees (Folder 5.55)
    - R: Trustees (Folder 5.56)
    - T: Trustees (Folder 5.57)
    - W: Trustees (Folder 5.58)
    - Trustees' Committees (Folder 5.59)
    - Trustees' Art Committee (Folder 5.60)
    - Trustees' Building Committee (Folder 5.61)
    - Committee on Endowment (Folder 5.62)
    - Committee on Endowment (Folder 5.63)